ukdirectory.co.uk 2008-05-13

# UK Directory - search the largest online directory of reviewed sites in the UK.

## Introduction

UK Directory ([http://www.ukdirectory.co.uk](http://www.ukdirectory.co.uk/)) is owned and operated by Crystal Guides Ltd, a limited company registered in England and Wales.

Crystal Guides Ltd considers Internet user privacy and data protection to be of paramount importance. Crystal Guides Ltd complies with the Data Protection Act 1998 in relation to all processing of personal data supplied to us by users and other personal data in our possession for any reason. We have registered with and notified the Data Protection Commissioner of our practice affecting personal data.

This statement discloses the privacy policy for Crystal Guides Ltd. This statement does not extend to sites that are linked to or which are not part of UK Directory.

## Cookies

A 'cookie' is a small amount of data, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on you computer’s hard drive. Cookies do not damage your computer. Each web site can send its own cookie to your browser if your browser’s preferences allow it, but (to protect your privacy) your browser only permits a web site to access the cookies it has already sent to you, not the cookies sent to you by other sites. You can decide if you want to accept cookies by changing the settings on your browser: to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, or notify you when a cookie is set.

Crystal Guides Ltd uses cookies to assign identification to your individual browser. This identifies your browser – but not you – to our servers every time you visit UK Directory. Cookies by themselves cannot be used to find out the identity of any user. Unless you voluntarily advise us, Crystal Guides Ltd will never know who you are, even though we assign your browser a cookie.

The information gathered through the use of cookies, allows Crystal Guides Ltd to offer a quality Internet service and easily accessible online content to our users, and to catalogue traffic patterns throughout UK Directory in a manner that provides personal privacy protection.

We also keep track of your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer UK Directory. Your IP address is also used to gather broad demographic information about you, such as your location and ISP. Crystal Guides Ltd may also collect aggregate information on how our users are utilising UK Directory.

Third party sites listed on UK Directory also have the ability to assign a different cookie to your browser in a process that Crystal Guides Ltd does not control. Again, unless you voluntarily advise them, these sites will also never know who you are. 

## Personal Information

At specific times Crystal Guides Ltd may ask you to provide us with personal information, including but not limited to your name and email address. You may choose not to provide us with this information; however, this may limit our ability to provide you with a specific service or offer you personalised content.

Please note that all the information you provide to Crystal Guides Ltd will be stored and processed in the United Kingdom in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998.

Occasionally we will send you email communications to provide information, which we think you will find useful, including information about new products and services from Crystal Guides Ltd. It is our policy only to send emails to customers who give us permission to do so. Our site provides you with the opportunity to "opt-out" of receiving communications from Crystal Guides Ltd at the time we ask you for this information. In addition, whenever we contact you via email, we will also have instructions on how to unsubscribe so that you will not receive any future emails from us if you so choose.

Third party sites listed on UK Directory may collect information about you when you view or click on their advertising or content. Crystal Guides Ltd does not control this collection of information. You should contact these advertisers or content providers directly if you have any questions about their use of this information. Additionally, Crystal Guides Ltd does not control the information collection and distribution policies on sites listed on UK Directory, although we do encourage our co-branding partners to adopt privacy policies similar to this one.

## Sharing Of Data

Crystal Guides Ltd will not disclose any of your personal information to a third party without your consent, unless we believe, in good faith, that the law requires it or that the rights or property of Crystal Guides Ltd need to be protected.

## Links To Other Sites

UK Directory contains links to other sites not affiliated with Crystal Guides Ltd. These sites have their own policies and practices with respect to online privacy, and Crystal Guides Ltd cannot be responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these websites. In addition, in certain instances, a Crystal Guides Ltd advertiser may ask you for personal information. Crystal Guides Ltd cannot be held responsible for the privacy practices of its advertisers; however, Crystal Guides Ltd encourages our partners and advertisers to adopt privacy policies similar to our own.

## Comment

We suggest that you practise reasonable discretion with any site when providing site operators/owners with personal information. It should also be noted that whenever you post personal information in publicly accessible places, such as chat rooms or message boards, this information becomes available to anyone with access to the Internet. Therefore, we recommend that you refrain from posting any information that you do not want seen in these public areas. You should feel free to contact any site that requests personal information from you if you have any questions regarding its policies.

Back to Homepage
